A Guide to the John Janney Papers, 1811-1994 (Bulk 1840-1880)
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
- Correspondence, 1836-1907.
  - John Janney Letters, 1828-1871
    - Letters to Janney from McVeigh in Alexandria, 1847-1850. (Box-folder 7:18)
      December 23, 1849
      August 27, 1850
  - John Janney Legal Letters and Court Cases, 1847-1860.
    - John Janney Papers, 1847. (Box-folder 7:19)
      January 1, Baltimore, Griffin vs. FJ Canrad
      June 3, Georgetown, Keutz vs. Benlty?
      June 5, Alexandria, McVeigh vs. Green
    - John Janney Papers, 1847. (Box-folder 7:20)
      January 6, Baltimore, from Hamibliton Bueky
      January 26, Goe stephenson vs. Rhodes
      May 5, Richmond, Johnson vs. Selday Estate
      June 21, Philadelphia, Wood vs. McVeigh
    - John Janney Papers, 1847. (Box-folder 7:21)
      February 10, Forest Hill, from HH Hamilton
      August 14, Alexandria, West vs. Beard
      August 28, Charlestown, from Andrew Hunter
      October 12, Miday, from HH Hamilton
      November 24, Forest Hill, from HH Hamilton
    - John Janney Papers, 1848. (Box-folder 7:22)
      January 4, Bell vs. Menern?
      April 23, from Thomas ?
      May 5, Baltimore, Warren Fisher vs. Tyler Estate
      May 12, Richmond, Johnson vs. Seldon
      June 16, Englick
    - John Janney Letters, 1848. (Box-folder 7:23)
      March 25, from J Whittens
      August 17, Baltimore, Wilson & Hopkins vs. White
      September 14, Alexandria, Green vs. Riudnck?
      October 19, Baltimore, from Comfort Tiffany
      November 29, Baltimore, Brown vs. Mount
      December 8, from Mortiruer Ashburn
      December 9, Baltimore, Brown vs. Feagauae?
      December 10, Salem, from Benjamin Hawley
      From J Whittens
    - John Janney Letters from Brogla(?), 1849. (Box-folder 7:24)
      February 22
      October 26
    - John Janney Letters, 1849. (Box-folder 7:25)
      April 14, Baltimore, from Glen McGinkey?
      April 21, from DH ?
      March 22, Baltimore, Alreen?
      September 24, Baltimore, from Stanley
      December 18, Clarksville, from Johnson
    - John Janney Letters, 1850. (Box-folder 8:1)
      February 12, Baltimore, Harvey vs. Benedsen
      February 16, Baltimore, Bayne & Withers vs. McPherson
      February 16, Baltimore, Dallan & Miller vs. McPherson
      March 1, Clarksville, from Johnson
      March 13, Alexandria, Thomas vs. Befdons?
    - John Janney Letters, 1850. (Box-folder 8:2)
      December 2, Salem, Murphy vs. Waton
      December 6, Richmond, M Goddwin
      September 5, from Rob Pizton
      September 24, Gordonsdale, from Rob Pizton
    - John Janney Letters, 1851. (Box-folder 8:3)
      July 31, Leesburg, from M Harris
      October 14, Alexandria, Smoot & Whaler vs. George Brown
      October 17, Alexandria, Phineas Janney vs. M. Galloway
      December 8, Princes Estates, from John White
    - John Janney Letters, 1852. (Box-folder 8:4)
      April 19, Washington, William Purell
      May 10, Baltimore, Hopkins vs. Stautintinger?
    - John Janney Letters, 1853. (Box-folder 8:5)
      February 17, Baltimore, from B Ring
      February 22, Baltimore, Levening vs. Schooley ?
      Benedict vs. Gray
      Roden vs. Parenjen ?
    - John Janney Letters, 1854. (Box-folder 8:6)
      April 15, Republic?, from John Powell
      July 7, from John Rice
      August 12, from R. Miller
    - John Janney Letters, 1855. (Box-folder 8:7)
      November 7, Millwood, Clark vs. Cooke
      November 17, Del. From M Bradford
    - John Janney Letter, Middleburg, from Rogers, April 19, 1856. (Box-folder 8:8)
    - John Janney Letters, 1857. (Box-folder 8:9)
      February 24, Baltimore, Daniel Buckey vs. Sell
    - John Janney Letters, 1858-1859. (Box-folder 8:10)
      January 1, 1858, Statement of Saluruy
      April 17, 1859,Jefferson Co., A Osburn
      May 24, 1859, Alexandria, unreadable
    - John Janney Letters, 1860. (Box-folder 8:11)
      January 5, Oakland, D.C. Tabb
  - Letters to Charles Miller (Law Partner), 1849-1850.
    - Charles Miller Letters, 1849. (Box-folder 8:12)
      March 8, Alexandria, Jaminson vs. McPherson
      April 12, Alexandria, Green vs. ?
      July 28, Baltimore
      September 18, Alexandria, From RS Douglas
    - Charles Miller Letter, May 9, 1860. (Box-folder 8:13)
  - Court Cases, 1813-1850.
    - Court Cases, 1835-1836. (Box-folder 8:14)
      Alexander vs. Weeks, May 20, 1835
      John Roberts vs. EJ Lee—April 18, 1836, Alexandria
      David Jones vs. Thomas Noland—May 2, Harrisonburg
      Matt Houner vs. John Wilson—June 29, Philadelphia
      Wm Moffatt vs. J Beard—September 14, Broadway
    - Court Cases, 1937. (Box-folder 8:15)
      Pittman vs. John Ish, February 12, Baltimore
      Wray vs. Lenening & Rust, July 1, Philadelphia
      Liverman vs. Rust&July 28, Baltimore
      Mercer vs. Shinner
      J&W Irvin vs. Thomas Livarm?
    - Court Cases, 1838. (Box-folder 8:16)
      Wm Miller vs. ?—February 12, Alexandria
      David Flowell vs. PL Lott—February 15, Charlestown
      Jonathan Janney vs. Lauch Mcleanty—May 15, Alexandria
      Chas Fisher vs. Jonathan Weirner—May 30, Baltimore
      G Benkeley vs. ?—July 10
      Smith vs. Ish—July 12, Charlestown
      Thomas Gitting vs. John Barvett—November 14, Rockville
    - Court Cases, 1839. (Box-folder 8:17)
      Kinsey Zenas vs. Tho Stance—January 35, Alexandria
      George Gill vs. George Price—April 22, Baltimore
      Chase & Facuner vs. E Francis—November 15, Baltimore
    - Court Cases, 1840. (Box-folder 8:18)
      Liverman vs. Chamblin—February 17, Baltimore
      William Dannel vs. Tho Gapany Estate—May 23, Danstown
      Rheinhart vs. D Lee—June 19
      Keinles vs. Sell Bajs—June 27, Baltimore
      David Thomson vs. B Smith—August 21, Baltimore
      McKnight vs. Heston—September 1, Alexandria
    - Court Cases, 1840. (Box-folder 8:19)
      Anderson vs. Jacobs & Fillen—September 17, Hapers Ferry
      Hodridge vs. Rupell—October 5 Baltimore
      James Awing vs. Wildman—October 24, Baltimore
      William Baken vs. Lewis—October 31, Upperville
      RW Ikaukan? vs. Cooper—Nov 12, Tiffin
      Baldwin & Lee vs. Wildman & Wood & Gibson vs. Lane—December 1, Philadelphia
      Unknown vs. Wildman&December 2, Baltimore
    - Court Cases, 1841. (Box-folder 8:20)
      Hugh Smith vs. John Canter—February 4, Alexandria
      Rob Walker Vsell Bojs—February 15, Philadelphia
      Taylor vs. Sell—November 2, Alexandria
      Beth Richard vs. Shnat & Skinner
    - Court Cases, 1841. (Box-folder 8:21)
      Joseph Barry vs. James Hamilton—June 7, Baltimore
      John Roberts vs. Powell—June 19, Alexandria
      Magruder & Dalynfile? vs. Smith & Skinner—June 21, Baltimore
    - Court Cases, 1841. (Box-folder 8:22)
      McVeigh vs. Sheine & Divine—August 9, Alexandria
      Chase vs. Fell Weadon—August 14, Baltimore
      Hanson vs. Edwards—December 4, Fredrick
    - Court Cases, 1842. (Box-folder 8:23)
      Walter Smoot vs. John Smart—January 1
      Union Bank Georgetown vs. CF Menson—January 17, Georgetown
      Wathins, Dugan, & Rust vs. A Sanders—February 21, Baltimore
      ? vs. Bajs—March 3, Baltimore
      Wyeth & Norris vs. Bajs—March 3, Baltimore
      Wyeth & Norris vs. Bajs—March 14, Baltimore
      Walker vs. Bajs—March 21, Philadelphia
      Williams vs. Fill Weadon—March 24, Baltimore
      B Waters vs. B Shinens?—April 9, Alexandria
      Mattingly vs. Launders—October 1, Hancock
      Wathnis & Rust vs. Weeken—November 21, Baltimore
    - Court Cases, 1842. (Box-folder 8:24)
      Sewell vs. Sam—May 5
      Kilheart vs. Ish—July 10, Alexandria
      Brocjman? vs. Skinner—September 9, Philadelphia
      Binvell vs. Dacnell—June 18, Liverpool
      Union Bank vs. Smart—November 23
      Hoffman vs. Hough
      Caldwell vs. John Carter
    - Court Cases, 1843. (Box-folder 8:25)
      McFarland vs. Mason—January 13, Washington
      Galdbonargh vs. Lwann's estate—February 16, Washington
      June 5,from the sheriff of Loudoun County
      Owing vs. Mathews—June 10, Baltimore
      Brooks vs. Silas Garnett—June 19, Baltimore
    - Court Cases, 1843. (Box-folder 8:26)
      Vacuell vs. Mairnac—May 15
      Holmes vs. Strickley—September 19, Montg
      John Roberts vs. Parnell—September 28, Alexandria
      John Clarke vs. William Richards—November 3, Bamericle
      Wheeler vs. Mathews—November 22, Alexandria
      Berkely vs. James Smith—December 12, St Louis
      O'Donnell vs. Wright—December 19, Baltimore
    - Court Cases, 1843. (Box-folder 12:10)
      April 30, can not read
      Price vs. Manton
    - Court Cases, 1844. (Box-folder 9:1)
      Tiffany vs. Broaddas & Son—February 19, Baltimore
      McVeigh vs. Rust—March 18, Alexandria
      Richard H. Lee—March 26, Washington
      Marmaduke vs. Hugh—March 30, Shepardstown
      Mccauley vs. Amos Janney—April 17, Baltimore
      Richard Smith vs.—April 19, Washington
      Dannel vs. Littleton—April 20, White Hall
      Goldsbourgh vs. Sivs?—May 17, Washington
      Edward Upton vs. Susan Berkley—May 28
      Webb vs. Unknown—June 18
      Reynolds & Smith vs. B?—December 4, Baltimore
    - Court Cases, 1845. (Box-folder 9:2)
      Vainell vs. Buinles—January 14, Alexandria
      McVeigh vs. Ish—January 23, Alexandria
      Seale vs. Love, January 19
      Wejlie & Wilson vs. Matthews—July 25, Baltimore
      Wheeler vs. Bajs & Mason—March 23, Lynn
      Gordon Schooley
      McCormick & Tiddall vs. ?—April 8, Berryville
      Love vs. Veale
      Toles vs. Janney
      Neal vs. Lowe
    - Court Cases, 1845. (Box-folder 9:3)
      Sutton & Harding vs. Beand—March 3, Baltimore
      Watkum & Rust vs. Mack—May 6, Baltimore
      R Shanhan vs. David Leapun—June 11
      Bayhman vs. Wright—June 17, Baltimore
      Brooks vs. W & J Wright—June 19, Baltimore
      Griffith FS Muntsin—August 26, Georgetown
      Wooll Innskeep vs. Hoffman & Wickis—September 5, Philadelphia
      Owings vs. Rust vs. Buckey vs. Mead vs. Bajo & Mead—November 20, Baltimore
    - Court Cases, 1846. (Box-folder 9:4)
      Walker vs. Ish—January 31, Baltimore
      Hough vs. John ?—February 18
      Pendleton vs. John Smith—March 19, Baltimore
      Baughman vs. Garnett—April 3, Baltimore
      Pittman vs. Ish—July 3, Baltimore
    - Court Cases, 1846. (Box-folder 9:5)
      Tiffnay & Rym vs. G Brca?—May 1, Baltimore
      Johnson vs. Seldon—May16, Richmond
      Lowe vs. Veale—July 16
      Richard Smith vs. E Peacock—September 10, Washington
      Poulson vs. Taylor—October 1, Baltimore
      Hanson vs. Whitmon—November 3, Fredrick
      Walkins & Rush
      J Inshoes vs. Wildman
    - Court Cases, 1865-1869. (Box-folder 9:6)
      Ball vs. Myer, August 26, 1865
      Green vs. Garrett, 1866
      To Robert Damo from Veale, 1867
      To Gov. Walter Smith, 1867
      Reed vs. Noland, 1869
    - Miscellaneous Cases. (Box-folder 9:7)
    - Court Case notes signed by Janney. (Box-folder 9:8)
      Patts vs. Bell
      Thomas Nickolls vs. Nathan Greg
      Carters vs. Drake
    - Legal Letters in German. (Box-folder 9:9)
    - Coroner's report in defense of Scott Bradley. (Box-folder 9:10)
    - Wheeler vs. Bennetts, Alexandria, April 26, 1850. (Box-folder 9:11)
    - Court Cases against William Wheeler. (Box-folder 9:12)
      Wheeler vs. Bennetts
      Wheeler vs. Smith
    - Court Case of Lee vs. Chichester. (Box-folder 9:13)
    - Court Case of Richard Duffield vs. Francis Deleyea. (Box-folder 9:14)
    - Court Case of Colston vs. Merrick. (Box-folder 9:15)
    - Court Cases of John W. Keinkle vs. Amos Gulick, 1833. (Box-folder 9:16)
      March 6, Baltimore
    - Cases involving Schooley. (Box-folder 10:1)
      Bann vs. Schooley
      Braden vs. Schooley
    - Court Cases involving Sam Boss. (Box-folder 10:2)
      John Keivle vs. Boss, December 4, 1837—Baltimore
      John Keivle vs. Boss, January 18, 1839—Baltimore
      JC Langston vs. Boss, November 13, 1839—Baltimore
      Brooks & Hatehkifs vs. Boss, December 21, 1837—Baltimore
      Richards & Betts vs. Boss, August 8, 1839—Baltimore
      Dovernus Lugdams vs. Boss, January 1, 1839—New York
      Richard Sewell vs. Boss, August 21, 1837—Baltimore
      Account list for Sam Boss
    - Cases involving Rupell and Clending, 1838, n.d. (Box-folder 10:3)
      Edward Mats vs. Rupell & Clending
      Aldridge Higdan vs. Rupell & Clending, January 13, 1838—Fredericktown
      Rupell vs. Cranpton?
    - Cases involving William & Wright, 1837-1838. (Box-folder 10:4)
      Fickey & Pauls vs. William & Wright, July 19, 1837—Baltimore
      Groverinon & Sons vs. William & Wright, April 19, 1838-Baltimore
    - Cases involving George Smoot, 1837, 1939. (Box-folder 10:5)
      Smoot vs. LM Kenner, July 9, 1839—Alexandria
      Smoot vs. James Wages, November 29, 1837—Alexandria
    - Cases involving Barry Liverman & Co., 1838. (Box-folder 10:6)
      Liverman vs. Jonathan Weirner, May 9, 1838—Baltimore
      Liverman vs. rL Arimistead, September 13, 1838—Baltimore
      Liverman vs. Jonathan Weirner, December 24, 1838—Baltimore
    - Cases involving Allan Griffith, 1837-1839. (Box-folder 10:7)
      Griffith vs. RL Armistead, November 30, 1838—Baltimore
      Griffith vs. Rupell, November 14, 1839
      Letter from Griffith to Janney, October 11, 1837—Baltimore
    - Cases involving Egeriton and Morris, 1832, 1837. (Box-folder 10:8)
      Egeriton & Morris vs. John Studen, March 24, 1837—Baltimore
      Mooris & Egeriton vs. Edmund Dorney, December 11, 1832—Baltimore
    - Court Cases of Long vs. Lovets. (Box-folder 10:9)
    - Cases involving Richard Sewell, 1836-1837. (Box-folder 10:10)
      Sewell vs. Amos Bexls—February 23, 1837, Baltimore
      Sewell vs. Isaac Holmes—February 4, 1836, Baltimore
    - Cases involving the Hopkins Brothers, 1836-1838. (Box-folder 10:11)
      Hopkins vs. Powell—August 18, 1836; Baltimore
      Hopkins vs. WD Dirsh—October 28, 1837; Baltimore
      Hopkins vs. WD Dirsh—August 26, 1837; Baltimore
      Hopkins vs. WD Dirsh—September 23, 1837; Baltimore
      Hopkins vs. WD Dirsh—November 29, 1837; Baltimore
      Hopkins vs. Saffen—November 16, 1837; Baltimore
      Hopkins vs. Weaks—March 17, 1838; Baltimore
      Hopkins VSSell McGthany—August 23, 1838; Baltimore
      Hopkins vs. Weeks & Edmands—November 30, 1838; Baltimore
      Hopkins vs. WD Dirsh—December 24, 1838; Baltimore
    - Cases involving the Hopkins Brothers, 1839-1840. (Box-folder 10:12)
      Hopkins vs. John Janney—January 24, 1839; Baltimore
      Hopkins vs. W Clending—January 13, 1839; Baltimore
      Hopkins vs. J Young—February 15, 1839; Baltimore
      Hopkins vs. Clending—March 4, 1839; Baltimore
      Hopkins vs. Canten—June 7, 1839; Baltimore
      Hopkins vs. John Janney—May 29, 1840; Baltimore
      Hopkins vs. J Weinner—June 19, 1840; Baltimore
      Hopkins vs. WD Dirsh—September 10, 1840; Baltimore
      Hopkins vs. E Waltman—September 19, 1840; Baltimore
      Hopkins vs. E Schooley—October 24, 1840; Baltimore
    - Cases involving the Hopkins Brothers, 1841-1843. (Box-folder 10:13)
      Hopkins vs. James Whaley—February 11, 1841; Baltimore
      Hopkins vs. Caldwell—June 10, 1841; Baltimore
      Hopkins vs. John Janney—July 1, 1841; Baltimore
      Hopkins vs. WD Dirsh—August 9, 1841; Baltimore
      Hopkins vs. J Harding—December 18, 1841; Baltimore
      Hopkins vs. Clark & White-March 24, 1842; Baltimore
      Hopkins vs. White—April 28, 1842; Baltimore
      Hopkins vs. Rust—February 4, 1843; Baltimore
      Hopkins vs. Rust—June 10, 1843; Baltimore
      Hopkins vs. Sundries—September 1, 1843; Baltimore
    - Cases involving the Hopkins Brothers, 1845-1846, 1870. (Box-folder 10:14)
      Hopkins vs. John Smith—March 25, 1845; Baltimore
      Hopkins vs. Galloway—March 15, 1845; Baltimore
      Hopkins vs. Miller Bell—November 29, 1845; Baltimore
      Hopkins vs. Humphrey—December 16, 1845; Baltimore
      Hopkins vs. Taylor—1845; Baltimore
      Hopkins vs. Mc?—July 22, 1846; Baltimore
      Hopkins vs. MD Dirsh—December 19, 1846; Baltimore
      Hopkins letter—April 27, 1870; Waterford
      Hopkins letter—April 29, 1870; Baltimore
    - Cases and letters involving the Owens Brothers, a group of Socialist Utopians, 1839-1846. (Box-folder 12:8)
      September 4, 1839; New Harmony,Indiana, from the Owen Brothers
      May 12, 1840, New Harmony, Indiana, From the Owens Brothers
      September 16, 1840; New Harmony, Indiana, from the Owens Brothers
      December 14, 1840; New Harmony, Indiana, from Owen Brothers
      November 5, 1841; New Harmony, Indiana, from the Owens Brothers
      Wildman vs. Owen Brothers—May 2, 1842; Washington
      June 4, 1844; Canvis, Illinois, from EB Webb
      July 2, 1845; Canvis, Illinois, from EB Webb
      April 7, 1846; Canvis, Illinois, from WB Webb
      April 29, 1846; Canvis, Illinois, from EB Webb
      May 18, 1846; Canvis, Illinois, from EB Webb
      Letter from Janney
    - Letters and Cases involving General Walter Smith—Smith served in the War of 1812, most known for the Battle of Bladensburg in the defense of Washington, 1841-1846. (Box-folder 12:9)
      December 30, 1841; Georgetown, from Smith to Janney
      April 18, 1842; Georgetown, from Smith to Janney
      September 16, 1842; Georgetown, from Smith to Janney
      December 20, 1842; Augusta, to William Fulton from Ben Bridgman
      April 18, 1844; Georgetown, from Smith to Janney
      October 4, 1845; Broad Run, to Smith from unknown
      October 5, 1845; Broad Run, to Smith form McKenna
      October 17, 1845; Georgetown, from Smith to Janney
      November 28, 1845; Georgetown, from Smith to Janney
      December 8, 1845; Georgetown, from Smith to Janney
      March 2, 1847; Georgetown, from Smith to Janney
      March 7, 1846; Georgetown, from Smith to Janney
      From Smith
    - Will of John Binns—Should free slaves by taking them to Maryland or another state; wife can keep young slaves until they turn 25, 1813. (Box-folder 12:3)
    - Deposition of A. Sidney Tebbs. (Box-folder 10:15)
    - Account Ledgers. (Box-folder 10:16)
  - Miscellaneous Letters, 1865-1886, n.d.
    - Miscellaneous letters, 1865. (Box-folder 11:1)
      From Mary ?; December 31
      From Sean Reg; December 29
    - Miscellaneous letters, 1866. (Box-folder 11:2)
      From John Carroll Dirsh; August 3
      From Sue; January 1
    - Letter on Senate Chamber letterhead, 1868. (Box-folder 11:3)
    - Miscellaneous letters, 1869. (Box-folder 11:4)
      Accounts from John and George Robinson
      Payment sheet for unknown
    - Miscellaneous letters, 1879-1886. (Box-folder 11:5)
      Mary Aslem to her Aunt—January 26, 1879; Baltimore
      From A Miller to her Sister—July 7, 1879
      From unknown to her sister—January 26, 1880; Baltimore
      Copy of a Bill—September 16, 1886
    - Miscellaneous letters (Box-folder 11:6)
      From sister M
      To May from M.A.L.
      From Belle
    - Miscellaneous letters (Box-folder 11:7)
      From Nath Seevery
      To Sam ? From Amos ?
    - Miscellaneous letters. (Box-folder 11:8)
    - Miscellaneous letters. (Box-folder 11:9)
    - Miscellaneous letters. (Box-folder 11:10)
    - Misecellaneous letters and checks. (Box-folder 11:11)
    - Miscellaneous items, 1865, n.d. (Box-folder 11:12)
      50 cent note issued from the town of Leesburg
      List of tariff fees adopted November 13, 1865
    - Miscellaneous items. (Box-folder 11:13)
    - Account ledgers. (Box-folder 12:1)
- Books, Periodicals, and Media, 1837-1845, n.d.
  - Books, 1837-1844, n.d.
    - Catalogue of Janney's books, 1837. (Box-folder 13:1)
    - Janney's business, account, and tariff book, 1844. (Box-folder 13:2)
    - Account book, 1830-1844. (Box-folder 13:3)
    - Quote and law book. (Box-folder 13:4)
    - Scrapbook. (Box 14)
    - Photograph book. (Box 15)
      page 1: 2 engravings
      page 2: Man and woman
      page 3: Prof Hardt and man
      page 4: Engraving and wife of Dr. Henry of Ashburn Farm
      page 5: Two boys
      page 6: Mr. And Mrs. Charles Miller
      page 7: Willie Morison of Warrenton, VA and his wife
      page 8: Mr. M Comb Wilmington from Leesburg Academy
      page 9: Charles Pollock (Alice's brother)
      page 9: Cousin Maude dau of Chas and Ellen Miller
      page 10: Man
      page 11: House and woman
      page 12: Rev. Walter W. Williams, church Pastor of Leesburg VA and James W. Janney (John Janney's brother)
      page 13: Dr. James W. Taylor of Hillsboro, VA and Cousin Maude
      page 14: Pope Pius IX and man
      page 15: CSA General Eppa Hunter and man
      page 16: CSA Col. John S. Mosby
      page 17: Man
      page 18: CSA General Robert E. Lee
      page 19: Dr. Sam B. Henry, of Ashburn Farm on horseback, and Nellie Glazer
      page 20: Nannie Bededict of Leesburg and a women
      page 21: Martha Washington and a women
      page 22: 2 photos of Mildred Covell
      page 23: Unknown
      page 24: Unknown
      page 25: Unknown
      page 26: Mrs. Charlotte Lee and Child
      page 27: Unknown
      page 28: Mrs. Walter W. Williams and John Janney the 2nd (John Janney's Nephew)
      page 29: Nathaniel E. Janney (John Janney's brother) and Mary Anne Osburn
      page 30: Miss Mollie Hough of Leesburg and the wife of Dr. Henry
      page 31: Unknown
      page 32: Aunt Annie Miller of Alexandria and unknown man
      page 33: Mrs. Howard Shackleford and William Monson of Warrantion
      page 34: Mrs. Waterman and unknown man
      page 35: R.J. Janney and unknown women
      page 36: Unknown
      page 37: Unknown
      page 38: Mrs. Scott Siddons and Will Brown
      page 39: Mrs. Schackleford
      page 40: Unknown
    - Household ledger, including names, ages, and shoe sizes of slaves. (Box-folder 16:1)
    - Pictures. (Box-folder 16:2)
      Two pictures of John Janney
      Old Stone Church in Leesburg
  - Periodicals, 1838-1845, n.d.
    - Metropolitan magazine, 1838-1841. (Box 17)
      December 1838, Vol. VI, No. VI
      January 1840, Vol. IX, No. I
      February 1840, Vol. IX, No. II
      March 1840, Vol. IX, No. III
      April 1840, Vol. IX, No. IV
      May 1840, Vol. IX, No. V
      June 1840, Vol. IX, No. VI
      July 1840, Vol. X, No. I
      August 1840, Vol. X, No. II
      September 1840, Vol. X, No. III
      October 1840, Vol. X, No. IV
      November 1840, Vol. X, No. V
      December 1840, Vol. X, No. VI
      January 1841, Vol. LI, No. I
      February 1841, Vol. XL, No. II
      March 1841, Vol. XL, No. III
      April 1841, Vol. XI, No. IV
      May 1841, Vol. Xi, No. V
      June 1841, Vol.XI, No. VI
      July 1841, Vol. XII, No. I
      August 1841, Vol. XII, No. II
      September 1841, Vol. XII, No. III
      October 1841, Vol. XII, No. IV
      November 1841, Vol. XIL, No. V
      December 1841, Vol. XIL, No. VI
    - London and Westminster Review, 1839. (Box 17)
      April 1839, Vol. VI, No 2.
      October 1839, Vol. VII, No 1.
    - Ecclectic Museum of Foreign Literature, 1842-1843. (Box 17)
      January 1842
      February 1842
      March 1842
      April 1842
      May 1842
      June to Nov 1842
      December 1842
      March 1843
      April 1843
      May 1843
      June 1843
      July 1843
      August 1843
      September 1843
      October 1843
      November 1843
      December 1843
    - Niles' National Register, 1845. (Box 18)
      March 1, 1845, Fifth Series, No. 26, Vol. XVIII, Whole No. 1,744
      March 8, 1845, Fifth Series, No. 1, Vol. XVIII, Whole No. 1,745
      March 15, 1845, Fifth Series, No 2, Vol. XVIII. Vol. LXVIII, Whole No. 1,746
      March 22, 1845, Fifth Series, No 4, Vol. XVIII. Vol.LXVIII, Whole No. 1,747
      March 29, 1845, Fifth Series, No. 4, Vol. XVIII. Vol. LXVIII, Whole No. 1,74
      April 5, 1845, Fifth Series, No 5, Vol. XVIII. Vol. LXVIII, Whole No. 1,749